Duygu Yagmur Efe



Contact

Address:

Karşıyaka-Izmir/ Turkey

Phone:

+90 505 183 10 94

Email:

duyguyagmurefe@gmail.com

Education

Dokuz Eylul University – Computer Engineering MSc 2020-Present

Celal Bayar University-Computer Programming 2017-2019

Celal Bayar University – Economics 2011-2016

Summary

Automation Engineer with 2+ years of hands-on experience in architecting automating and optimizing mission-critical deployments over large-scale infrastructure. Proficient with Configuration Management tools, and scripting for infrastructure workflow.

Skill Highlights

- Python, PHP, Perl Script, SQL Relational Database.
- Linux-Unix
- The ELK, Zabbix, Grafana, Jaspersoft
- Docker, Kubernetes
- CI/CD, Git

Experience

Automation Engineer - 12/2020 to Present

Ericsson, Remote

- Automated setting up server infrastructure for the services using shell and python script.
- Migrate Data from Elasticsearch Cluster to using Logstash and Beat infrastructure design for the ELK Clusters.
- Created complex SQL queries to generate reports and provide insights into system behavior, assisting in troubleshooting and root cause analysis.
- Supported, maintained, and developed scripts for: MySQL back-end
- Develop automation solutions leveraging Shell, Perl, and Python Scripts to increase the operational efficiency

Software Test Engineer – 08/2020 to 12/2020 Turk Telekom Group, Izmir

- QA/Testing with specialization in testing of telecom billing applications and testing of web based & Client- Server applications, effective use of QA and Testing practices.
- Designing Test Cases and Test Scripts for Windows, Shell scripting and UNIX environments.
- Testing of Billing-Charging Backend system
- Preparation and Reporting of daily test status report, defect report, issue escalations to Release management and all stakeholders.

Junior Network Engineer – 02/2019 to 6/2019 General Directorate Of State Airports Authority, Izmir

- Conceived and implemented network wide OSPF, BGP and Policy Based Routing changes
- Developed entry level understanding of AD, cloud, server hardware/software, Citrix
- Responsible for checking all SNMP alerts on a daily basis and addressing or escalating anything beyond a warning severity.